片名：迫切的危机
目标方位020
Target bearing 0-2-0.
前进，020！
Contact, 0-2-0!
距离，两万码
Range, 20,000.
Range, 20,000 yards.
航向255
Course 2-5-5.
航向255，正确
Course 2-5-5 true.
速度，13海里
Speed, 13.
Speed, 13 knots.
盗贼
Cowboys.
第一小队，待命
Sally phase one, man the 60s.
（美国海岸巡逻队）
（巫师号，莫比尔）
“巫师号，莫比尔”
"Enchanter, Mobile."
跑太远了吧
Well, we're a long way from home.
对他们鸣笛！
Wake them up!
是海军！
It's the Navy!
快点，去拿国旗！
Quick, put out the flag!
巫师号
Enchanter,
这是美国海岸巡逻队
this is the United States Coast Guard.
停船，准备登船受检
Heave to and prepare to be boarded.
（巫师号）
巫师号
Enchanter,
你们挂美国船旗，我们要上船检查
you are a US flag ship and we are going to board you.
立刻停航
Heave to now.
请船员到船头集合
Muster your crew on the bow.
好了，站在那里
Okay, hold it there.
你们两个，往前走！
You two, report.
兰戴尔，跟我来
Randall, come with me.
别动
跪下！
Kneel down!
船长
Captain.
船长？
Captain?
请说，队长
Go ahead, Senior Chief.
情况不妙
It's a bad one.
赶快派人拿录影机来
I think you better send over the video camera.
（中情局总部，维吉尼亚州，兰利市）
杰克，进来吧
Jack, come on in.
你桌上的案件堆多高了？
How high is the pile on your desk?
差不多这么高
About this high.
现在更高了
Now it's this high.
又有什么案子？
What have you got?
听说南加勒比海的事了吗？
You heard about that business in the south Caribbean?
听说了
Yeah, a little bit.
我要全部的细节
I need the full skinny.
什么时候？
By when?
尽快
As soon as you can.
好吧
Okay.
- 杰克 - 什么事，长官？
- Jack. - Yes, sir.
要谨慎一点
Be discreet.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你会明白的
You'll find out.
真神秘
Mysterious.
我最爱神秘
I love a mystery.
杰克·莱恩
Ryan, John P.
让他通过
Let him through.
- 给你  - 谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
知道怎么走吧？
You know where you're going?
知道，谢谢
Yup. Thank you.
车要停哪里？
Oh, where do I park?
那里
Right over there.
谢谢
Thank you.
我在通道上，正往前走
Okay, I'm in the passageway, going forward.
- 小心台阶  - 经过主人舱房
- Watch your step. - Master stateroom.
甲板上有血渍
Got blood on the deck, blood on the sheets and below.
发现19颗子弹
Nineteen cartridges were recovered...
在下面的地上
Down there, sir. On the ground.
还有…
as well as the...
两支作案用的凶枪
As the two weapons that fired them.
我在甲板下
I'm below deck now...
血液采样跟船主一家人…
Blood samples taken consistent with...
吻合
the crew,
包括哈丁及其妻子
Hardin and his wife,
还有一对儿女
and his son and daughter.
我的床单和枕头上都有血
I got blood on both the sheets and pillow
在右舷和左舷…
on both starboard and portside racks...
（美国海岸巡逻队）
镜子上也有血渍
and there's some blood up there on the mirror, too.
他们是在主人舱房遇害的
They were killed in their staterooms,
显然当时在睡觉
apparently as they slept,
然后被拖到上层甲板，再扔到海里
dragged topside and thrown overboard.
两名束手就擒的嫌犯
The two men in custody surrendered
曾企图躲避巡逻队的缉捕
after a brief attempt to outrun the Coast Guard.
我们对嫌犯了解多少？
What do we know about them, the men in custody?
在波哥大因多次贩毒而被捕，总统先生
Half a dozen arrests for drug trafficking in Bogota, Mr. President.
贩毒…
Drugs.
怀疑和卡里的犯罪集团有关
Suspected ties to the Cali cartel
而不是梅德林…
not Medellin...
你还好吗，詹姆斯？
You all right, James?
根据缉毒署的资料
according to DEA.
为什么？
Why?
没什么，总统，只是杀人抢劫嘛
Nothing exotic, sir. Straight piracy and murder.
这又不是头一遭
It's not the first time.
这可是头一遭我的好友遇害
It's the first time it was a friend of mine.
是的，总统
Yes, sir.
你刚刚怎么了？没事吧？
What was that in there? Are you all right?
没事
Yeah.
老天，我36小时没睡了，刚才有讲清楚吗？
Geez, I haven't slept in 36 hours. I make any sense?
不知道耶，你刚讲了什么？
I don't know. What did you say?
开玩笑的，讲得很好
Just kidding. Good job.
你该上上交际课，巴比
You ought to give diplomacy lessons, Bobby.
我只是照实说 这是我的职责
I call it the way I see it. That's my job.
詹姆斯！
James.
他找你
And he's yours.
等我一下
Wait for me.
把门关上
Shut the door.
我向美国人民保证过
I promised the American people
要扼止毒品入侵这国家
I would do something about the drugs pouring into this country.
你有啊
You are.
我们协助哥伦比亚
We support the Colombians' efforts
对抗毒贩，提供设备而且…
against the cartels with equipment and...
而且一无所获！
And accomplish nothing.
这些毒贩怎么想？
What do these drug dealers think?
以为我们无能吗？是这样吗？
We're powerless, is that what they think?
他们自以为能为所欲为
They think they can keep doing this kind of thing
永远不受制裁！
and there's no response, ever.
你提议采取行动吗，总统？
Are you suggesting a course of action, sir?
我想提议的…
The course of action I'd suggest...
是我不能提议的
is a course of action I can't suggest.
这样我…
I'm...
不确定该怎么做
not sure where that leaves us.
贩毒集团对美国国家安全
These drug cartels represent a clear and present danger
是迫切的危机
to the national security of the United States.
（哥伦比亚，卡里市，埃内斯托·埃斯科贝多庄园）
柯特斯！柯特斯！
Cortez! Cortez!
知道你干了什么好事吗？
Do you know what you've done?
我杀了一个小偷
I killed a thief
我杀了一个偷我钱的…
a thief who was stealing
…臭小偷！
from me!
还有他太太、儿子、女儿
And his wife, and his son, and his daughter.
显然根本没顾虑到后果
Apparently with no thought of the consequences
哦，我好想等他的孩子长大
Oh, I want his kids to grow up
趁我没预料到时
and avenge their father's death
替他父亲报仇…
when I least expect it...
他是美国总统的
He was a good friend
好朋友
and political ally of the
兼政治伙伴
President of the United States
我不感到意外
That doesn't surprise me.
你至少该担心了
It should at the very least concern you.
他们能拿我怎样？
What are they going to do?
通缉我？逮捕我？
Come after me? Arrest me?
你在吓唬我
You're scaring me.
你能不能停下来好好听我说？
Will you stop long enough for me to tell you something important?
谢谢
Thank you.
听好，你请我当顾问
Listen, you pay me to counsel you,
我就该提供你意见
and I am counseling you.
我的情报能让你活命
I'm keeping you alive with information.
如果你不听我
Now, if you disregard my counsel,
继续照自己的方式经营生意
if you keep running your business the way you have been
只用子弹，不用脑袋
with your balls instead of your head,
就会有两种结果
two things will happen.
我闪人，你丧命
I'll quit, and you'll get killed.
你忘了跟我报告出差的结果
You forgot to tell me about your scouting trip.
我没忘
No, I didn't.
你又找了一个通风报信的 他是谁？
You made another contact. Who is he?
卡斯特罗也常问我，我的情报来源是谁
Castro always asked me the same question about my sources,
我总是给他一样的答案
and I always gave him the same answer.
对，但卡斯特罗付给你的钱没有我多
Yes, but Castro didn't pay you what I pay you.
这个人不用花你一毛钱
This one will cost you nothing.
女人
A woman.
你在利用女人
You're using a woman.
浮不起来！
It won't float!
约翰，你要吐司还是…？
John, what do you want, toast or...
松饼
Waffles.
我没时间做松饼
I don't have time for waffles.
- 你只能吃吐司  - 有没有看到我的钥匙？
- You can have toast or toast. - Anybody seen my keys?
不是在大厅桌上，就是在你口袋
They're either on the front hall table or in your pocket.
- 约翰  - 煎饼！
- John. - Pancakes!
我的钥匙呢？真是的
Now, where are my keys? Shoot.
- 给我吐司  - 谢谢
- Toast, please. - Thank you.
- 拜  - 拜，宝贝
- Bye. - Bye, honey.
- 拜，爸  - 拜，小家伙
- Bye, Dad. - Bye, pal.
- 爸，这不会浮  - 喂？
- Daddy, it won't float. - Hello?
- 是的  - 它不应该浮的
- Yes. - It's not supposed to float.
这是潜艇，在水里航行的船
It's a submarine. It's a boat that goes underwater.
- 爸  - 杰克
- Dad. - Jack.
喂？
Hello?
什么时候？
When?
（男性杂志，60件事）
本来以为是感冒
I thought I had the flu.
他们要是没告诉我，我还会以为是感冒
I'd still think I had the flu if they weren't telling me otherwise.
他们说了什么？
Well, what... What are they telling you?
恶性胰脏癌
Pancreatic cancer of an aggressive nature,
没听错的话
if I heard them right.
老天
Jesus.
那是什么意思？
Well, what does that mean?
我想意思是我快玩完了
I guess it means I'm in big trouble.
不，我是说可以切除吗？
No, I mean, can they... Can they operate or...
也许吧
Maybe.
他们说也许吧
That's what they said. "Maybe."
在我听来应该是不行
But it sounds suspiciously like "no" to me.
他就是他们其中一人
There's one of them now.
嘿，我还没挂掉
Hey, I'm not dead yet.
不过我人在医院
But I am in the hospital,
不在办公室
which means that I'm not in my office,
因此不知道局里的状况
which means I don't know what's going on.
我需要你驻守
I need you there.
- 哪里？  - 我的办公室，代替我的职务
- Where? - In my office, doing my job.
慢点，我…
No, wait. I...
我最讨厌在状况外，杰克，这点你知道
I hate not knowing what's going on, Jack. You know that.
我怕我不能胜任你的工作
I wouldn't know the first thing about doing your job, sir.
你一直都有参与，我们没秘密
You've been around. No big mystery.
你也去过白宫
You've been to the White House.
一次而已，而且我不喜欢
Once. I hated it.
不，才不是
No, you didn't.
想知道华府的政治哲学吗？
Want to know about politics in Washington?
四个字
Four words.
“小心为上”杰克
Watch your back, Jack.
巴比？
Bobby?
你应该要第一个知道
You should be the first to know,
也许是第三或第四个知道
or I guess the third or fourth to know.
我指派莱恩为情报局代理副局长
I'm appointing Ryan the Acting Deputy Director, Intelligence.
当然这是暂时的
Now, it'll be a provisional appointment, of course,
直到詹姆斯康复为止
until James recovers.
我要你尽快跟他说明
I want you to get him up to speed
我们对哥伦比亚的资助计划
on our aid program to the Colombians.
他要跟监督委员会报告
He's got to brief the oversight committee
说服他们再拨七千五百万的预算
and talk them out of another $75 million.
而且不能让他像个大傻瓜
And not make a complete fool out of himself.
哈丁家族谋杀案进行得如何？
What's happening on the Hardin murders?
我在处理中
I'm on it.
总统要求彻底调查
The President's calling for a full-court press.
那么你们俩要密切配合了
So, you guys are going to be working together, hand in hand.
太好了
That's great.
玛格丽特
Margaret.
他的东西留着吧
Why don't we leave all his things?
好的
Okay.
莱恩
Ryan.
令人难以置信！
I can't believe it!
你是指他不上道吗？
He's not a team player, is that what you're saying?
不只不上道
Not a team player?
还是个童子军
He's a Boy Scout.
该死的童子军
He's a goddamn Boy Scout.
相信忠诚、无私，还喜欢打童军绳
Believes in loyalty, cleanliness and knot tying.
那就把他排除在外
So leave him out of it.
他可是情报局副局长，詹姆斯
He's the Deputy Director of Intelligence, James.
这下有点麻烦了，你不觉得吗？
It's going to be a little tricky, don't you think?
怎么会？他需要知道什么？
Why? What does he need to know?
不需要
Nothing.
他什么都不需要知道
He needs to know nothing.
他也不会知道
He's going to know nothing.
我要一份拷贝，证明总统授权
I want a copy of the President's authorization
对犯罪集团采取新行动
of this new action against the cartels.
你要什么？
You want what?
你听到了
You heard me.
这件事他并不知情
He doesn't know about it.
让我跟你解释清楚
Let me explain it to you very simply.
这是你答应的，不是我
This is your deal, not mine.
除非我有授权书
So unless I have written authorization,
否则你没戏唱
this thing is over before it begins
因为我可不想在东窗事发时
because I'm not going to be the only one left
成为代罪羔羊
without a chair when the music stops.
（发文者：国家安全顾问）
（总统授权中情局副局长，罗伯特·里特）
（负责执行互惠行动包含…）
（目的：执行对抗卡里犯罪集团的准军事行动）
（詹姆斯·卡特）
（巴拿马，巴拿马市）
互惠行动
"Reciprocity."
真聪明的名字
That's a clever name for it.
复仇可是非常、非常危险的动机
Revenge is a very, very, very dangerous motivation.
你到底能不能负责执行这个行动？
Are you able to handle this operation or not?
我要的只是简单的能或不能
What I'm looking for here is a simple yes or no.
你要的是一场政治混乱
What you're looking for is a political mess.
- 能或不能？  - 这是他们要的吗？
- Yes or no? - Is that what they want?
因为这可要付出代价的
Because that's what this is.
第一任政府的人要的
They want what every first-term administration wants.
都是连任
A second term.
我想国会山庄的人不会同意的
I don't imagine the boys on the Hill have approved this.
对吧？
Have they?
你意思是不？
Is that a no?
可恶
Shit.
我要你立刻把钱汇到我的户头
I want the money in my account before I move an inch.
没问题
You got it.
- 我要一组卫星通讯  - 没问题
- I'll need a Comsat link. - You got it.
一支突击队
An insertion team.
- 你可以有一整支部队  - 我不要一整支部队
- You can have a brigade. - I don't want a frigging brigade.
我只要12名会打游击战的士兵
I just need 12 men who understand discretionary warfare.
特种部队，会说西班牙文
Special Ops people, Spanish speaking.
卡特会找到士兵
Cutter will get the military.
（华盛顿，杜勒斯机场）
- 你好吗，先生？  - 很好
- How are you today, sir? - Very well.
- 此行的目的是什么？  - 做生意
- And what is the purpose of your visit? - Business.
做什么生意？
What kind of business are you in?
我卖牵引机
I sell tractors.
我生产并销售牵引机
Well, I build them. Then I sell them.
你要停留多久？
And how long will you be staying?
几天吧
A few days.
（护照身分无误，姓名：兰达、罗伯托-阿隆诺）
当然有风险
Of course it's a risk.
我知道，不过还有什么选择？
I know it's a risk but what's the alternative?
在视网膜做大量放射线治疗吗？
Zapping a retina with 6,000 rads of cobalt?
那可不是闹着玩的
That is not a pretty picture.
总比癌细胞扩散到大脑好
Prettier than a tumor spreading into the cranial sac.
- 已经扩散到眼球了  - 她叫什么名字？
- Enough already about the eyeball. - What is her name?
我在吃午餐
I'm trying to have my lunch.
听好
Listen.
- 你饿了吗？  - 饿死了
- Hungry? - Starved.
因为我们可以省掉午餐
Because we could forget about lunch.
上回就是这样，记得吗？
Oh, we did that last time, remember?
我记得吗？你记得吗？
Do I remember? Do you?
模模糊糊的
Vaguely.
也许我该唤起你的记忆
Maybe I should refresh your memory.
也许吧，打扰一下
Maybe you should.
你的桌位准备好了
Excuse me? Your table is ready now.
让给别人吧，我来叫车
Give it to somebody else. I'll get a cab.
莫伊拉？
Moira?
我就知道是你
Oh, I thought that was you.
你好吗？杰克好吗？
How are you? How's Jack?
他很好
He's great, just great.
你还在联邦调查局工作？
You still with the FBI?
是的，替局长工作
Oh, yeah, in the Director's office.
那位是谁？
Who was that?
我的新朋友
My new friend,
罗伯托·兰达
Señor Roberto Landa.
他长得像不像杰克？
Doesn't he look like Jack?
哦，是吗？
Oh, does he?
- 我没看清楚  - 只是拉丁版的
- I can't quite see. - Only Latin.
拉丁版的杰克·莱恩？
A Latin Jack Ryan?
那我非看不可了
Oh, well, this I have to see.
我得走了，拜
I have to go. Bye.
我们知道这不是海盗
Well, we know it's not piracy.
海盗偷船
Pirates steal boats.
（游艇灭门惨案 哈丁全家人惨遭杀害）
这些家伙有迈阿密飞往波哥大的机票
These guys had plane tickets, Miami to Bogota
打算作案后隔天早上潜逃
the morning after the killings.
- 嘿，丹恩  - 情况如何？
- Hey, Dan. - How's it going?
我们在找犯罪动机
Well, we're sneaking up on a motive here.
这位是丹恩·穆雷探员
Dan Murray, Bureau.
拉尔夫·威廉，缉毒署
Ralph Williams, DEA.
有招供吗？
Said anything yet?
有 “我们是无辜的”
Yeah. "We're innocent."
等检查官跟他们提协议吧
Till the DA offers them a deal.
已经提过了
He already has.
普通的
Regular
还是酥脆的
or extra crispy.
他指的是炸鸡，也是电椅
He was either referring to fried chicken or the electric chair.
你认为是什么？
What are you picturing here?
正派的美国商人惨遭灭门？
A hit on a respectable American businessman and his family?
假设他是正派
You're assuming he's respectable.
（彼得·哈丁工业）
（本磁碟内容已译成密码）
（请输入使用者名称）
我们有…
We have...
备忘录
memos,
信件
letters,
信用卡帐单
credit card statements...
还有私人税单
And we got personal income tax,
- 公司税单…  - 话费单、公司章程
- corporate income tax... - phone bills, article of incorporation.
你破解密码所需的全部资料
Everything you could need to break his code.
这是什么？
What's... What's this?
国中毕业纪念册
Old high school yearbook.
女朋友、足球队
Sweethearts, football team.
有用吗？
You think?
我不知道
I don't know.
好吧，我们来试试看吧
Okay, let's see what we've got here.
- 没加奶精  - 没加奶精
- No cream. - There wasn't any cream.
人们最爱用生日日期，就从这个试起吧
People are big on birthdays. Let's start there.
我猜你的提款卡密码也是你的生日日期
I'll bet your ATM code is your birthday.
差不多
Close.
顺序颠倒吗？
In reverse?
好了，他的生日是…
All right, his birthday is...
真简单，不是吗？
That'd be too easy, wouldn't it?
试试顺序颠倒
Let's try it in reverse.
（使用者哈丁的密码 04-12-4密码无效）
不对
No.
他太太的生日
Wife's.
不对
No.
- 孩子的  - 这要花…
- Son's. - This could take...
- 好几个月  - 好几个月
- Months. - months.
儿子生日颠倒 你也是吧
Son's in reverse. This is for you.
不对，太太生日颠倒
No. Wife's in reverse.
女儿生日颠倒
No. Daughter's in reverse.
你得改掉提款卡密码
You got to change your ATM code.
不对，女儿…
No. Daughter's...
不对，太太…
No. Wife...
（密码02-21-84接受  使用者名称：哈丁）
找到了
Got it.
我找到了！
I got it!
在这里
Right here.
太太出生月份，女儿出生日期，儿子出生年份
Wife's birth month, daughter's day, son's year.
- 说真的  - 顺序没颠倒 抱歉
- No kidding. - But not in reverse. Sorry.
（哈丁股份明细）
- 把这个印出来，好吗？  - 好，长官
- Print me up that one, will you? - Yes, sir.
做得好
My boy.
然后三年前，哈丁收到一大笔…
And then three years ago, Hardin received a large infusion
海外投资资金
of foreign investment capital
他用这笔资金大量投资20家购物中心
which he invested wisely in 20 major shopping centers
从沃夫兹堡到亚特兰大都有
from Fort Worth to Atlanta.
我说大量是因为在经济衰退期间
I say "wisely" because in the middle of the recession,
他还能创造可观利润，比起国税局来说
he posted record profits, at least to the IRS,
他显然更怕自己的合伙人
who he apparently feared more than his own partners.
对他们来说
To them,
根据他给股东的报表…
according to the stockholder statements he was giving them,
购物中心的生意不太好
the shopping centers weren't doing nearly as well.
以前是
They were.
他却独吞大笔利润
He was just skimming the lion's share of the profits,
六亿五千万元
$650 million,
分别存在数个银行户头
and putting it in numbered accounts
有些在卢森堡、巴拿马
in Luxembourg, Panama,
有些在开曼群岛
and the Cayman Islands.
他们为了钱杀他
They killed him for it.
- 谁？ - 他的合伙人
- Who? - His partners.
谁是他的合伙人？
Who were his partners?
显然他…
Well, it seems clear that...
他帮哥伦比亚的贩毒集团洗钱
That he was laundering money for the Colombian drug cartels.
老天
Jesus!
我认识这个人四十年了
I knew the man for 40 years.
我们一起读书
We went to school together.
差点一起合伙做生意
We almost went into business together.
那会赚不少钱
That would have been good.
哦，老天，媒体一定会大做文章
Oh, man, the press is going to have a field day with this.
这房间之外没有人知道这件事
No one outside of this room knows anything about it.
会的
They will.
他们总是有办法知道
They always do.
媒体会找上门
It'll come out.
你说得完全正确
You're absolutely right about that.
不过到时候
But when it does,
我们会说你和哈丁交情不深
we'll downplay your relationship with Hardin somehow.
- 怎样？ - 怎样？
- What? - What?
回避问题
Defuse it.
- 什么？你不同意吗？ - 不是
- What? You disagree? - No.
其实，是的
Well, actually, yes.
恕我直言，但我会反其道而行
Forgive me, but I would go in the other direction.
要是记者问你和哈丁是不是朋友
If a reporter asked if you and Hardin were friends,
我会说“我们是好朋友”
I'd say, "No. We were good friends."
要是问你们是不是好朋友
If they should ask if you were good friends,
我会说“我们是一辈子好友”
I'd say, "No, no, we were lifelong friends."
我不会给他们做文章的空间
I would give them no place to go,
没什么好报导，没故事好编
nothing to report, no story.
我意思是事情已经发生了…
I mean, it's no sense defusing a bomb after it's already...
…回避是没用的
It's already gone off.
（加州，杭特利格特堡）
该死！可恶！
Damn. Shit!
你看见他吗？
You see him?
好吧
All right.
小组往左移两公尺
Move your team two meters to the left.
好了
That's it.
停
Stop.
摸摸浅色草堆
Touch that light-colored grass.
狙击手在你脚下
Sniper at your feet.
什么都没有，士官长
There's nothing here, Sergeant Major.
该死！
Damn!
他真行
He is good.
差一点，他怎么移动得这么快？
That was close. How's he moving so fast?
我看到他了 直直往前
I see him. Come in. Straight in.
快点！用跑的！
Now! Run!
继续往前！
Keep coming.
停
Stop.
往左边
To your left,
to your left.
停，狙击手在你脚下
And stop. Sniper at your feet.
不然是什么？
Well, what is it?
他在这里吃午餐，士官长
He had lunch here, Sergeant Major.
麦当劳汉堡 足三两
McDonald's. Quarter Pounder...
加起司
with cheese.
该死
Damn.
- 该死！ - 第四枪了
- Damn! - That's four.
好了，你赢了！
All right, you won this one!
出来吧！
Come on out!
士兵，你怎么能靠得这么近？
Soldier, how did you get that close to me?
狙击手本来就是神出鬼没
Sniper approached the instructor by being a sneaky bastard,
士官长！
Sergeant Major!
知道在加州乱丢垃圾
Do you know the fine for littering
要罚多少钱吗？
in the State of California, Chavez?
知道，长官！
Yes, sir!
我看到你在训练场的表现，你很行
I saw you on the sniper course. You looked good.
这里的任务快完成了，对吧，中士？
Just about finished here, aren't you, Sergeant?
对，长官
Yes, sir.
期待放长假跟年轻妻子及孩子团聚？
Looking forward to taking some leave with that young wife and kids?
我没有年轻妻子及孩子
I don't have any young wife and kids, sir.
你有什么？
What do you have?
你很少打电话
I mean, you don't call anybody with great frequency,
信件往来也很少
don't write many letters, don't receive them.
容我问一下，长官，你是谁？
Who are you, sir, if you don't mind my asking?
克拉克先生和我共同负责一个特殊任务
Mr. Clark and I are putting together a special mission
任务领导人要我的小组参与其中
and the group commander wants my team to be a part of it.
为期大约六个月
You'd be gone a couple of months, maybe six,
之后要是没死的话
after which, if you're not dead,
你可以选择加入特种部队
you'd have your choice of assignments in Special Ops.
总统先生，你有没有任何评论？
Mr. President, do you have a comment on...
总统先生！
Mr. President!
总统先生
Mr. President.
显然回避问题
And that appears to be defusing an issue
就会让问题愈滚愈大，成为另一个丑闻
that was snowballing into yet another scandal for this administration.
纽约时报报导
The New York Times is reporting
你和哈丁是好朋友
that you and Hardin were good friends.
是不是真的？
Is that true?
不，不仅如此
No, not quite.
我们不仅是好朋友
We weren't good friends.
还是一辈子的好朋友
We were lifelong friends.
那是我说的
I said that.
我叫他那么说的
I told him to say that.
怎样？
What?
我什么都没说
I didn't say anything.
- 对，但你心里在想  - 不
- Yeah, but you're thinking something. - No.
我只是被你今天刻意打扮
I was just distracted by how much trouble
分了心而已
you were having with your ensemble today.
- 你不必每天穿得…  - 快点，萨利，快点，走了
- Well, it's not every day... - Come on, Sally. Hurry up, we gotta go.
一副值得信任的样子
you have to look trustworthy.
- 谁跟谁说了什么，爸？  - 没什么
- Who told who to say what, Dad? - It's not important.
- 我可以自己走  - 我知道你可以
- I can walk myself. - I know you can.
- 总统吗？  - 是啊
- The President? - Yeah.
妈妈说她赚的钱比总统还多
Mom says she makes more money than the President.
拜，爸，再见
Bye, Dad. See you.
她也许是对的，再见
She's probably right. Bye.
莱恩博士，谢谢你今天下午
I want to thank you, Dr. Ryan, for the information
跟我们分享了这些资讯
you've shared with us this afternoon.
谢了，参议员
Thank you, Senator.
我同意我们必须协助哥伦比亚
I agree we have to help the Colombians
打击贩毒集团的活动
in their struggle to curtail the drug cartels' activities.
然而我不明白
However, I'm confused.
增加拨款如何让此计划
How do you see additional funds alone
从失败中起死回生？
advancing this program from the utter failure that it is?
明白我的意思吗？
You see what I'm getting at?
我恐怕不明白
No, I'm afraid I don't.
你刚说此计划我方完全采温和政策
You said this effort would be totally benign on our part.
报告上说得很清楚
Well, the finding clearly states
我方仅限于提供意见而已，参议员
that our assistance is limited to supply and advice only, Senator.
我知道，我看过了
I know. I've read that.
我这星期也看了
I've also read a similar finding,
35年前的一份类似报告
written 35 years ago this week,
关于在东南亚我们一无所悉的丛林
regarding a little-thought-of sliver of jungle in Southeast Asia.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
你拿我们的
You're comparing our request
反毒行动补助款申请案跟越战相比拟？
for supplemental anti-drug funds to Vietnam?
每次我都会这样比拟
I'm comparing it to every instance
在这种立法机构每次要对
a legislative body such as this is asked to
缺乏实证的案件做判断时
render judgment based on less than all the facts.
我不知道该说什么了
Well, I'm afraid I don't know what to say to that.
你可以跟我们保证
You could begin by assuring us
所有事实都已呈报
we have been given all the facts.
我想我是的
I thought I had.
你还可以进一步保证
You could further assure us, then,
这次增加的拨款
that this increase in funds,
或你说的补助款
this "escalation," to use your word,
将不会用在任何秘密的军事行动上
will not be used for any covert military action.
我不知道你怎么会这么想
I don't know how you're getting to this.
根据我丰富的经验
Long experience, sir.
绝不派兵
No troops, then.
我特别说清楚点，因为我不希望有任何误解
I enunciate that clearly because I don't want there to be any mistake.
绝不派兵
No troops.
你可以跟我保证吗？
You could say I have your word on that?
可以，因为我说话算话
You could, indeed, because you do.
- 数到三往下跳  - 好的
听好！
Listen up!
军籍牌！
Dog tags.
全部拿下来
Take them off.
往前传过来
Pass them forward.
检查口袋有没有任何辨别身分的物件
Check your pockets for anything that can be used for identification.
我们在陆地上空
We're feet dry.
看到降落点，请准备
LZ in sight. Get ready.
祝好运，去收拾他们吧！
Good luck, boys. Go get them.
准备降落了
Okay, let's take her down now. We're going down.
快！快！快！
Go! Go! Go!
（后备队罗伯特·里特有内部讯息，连接？是的）
（恭喜，詹姆斯，你的小小战争）
（已经展开了）
嘿，巴伯
Hey, Bob.
- 你好吗？  - 很好，先生
- How you doing? - Good, sir.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
- 早安，杰克  - 早安
- Good morning, Jack. - Good morning.
莱恩
Ryan,
进来吧
come on in.
认识大家吗？
You know everyone?
认识、认识
Yes, yes.
咖啡？面包？
Coffee, bagel?
黑咖啡，谢谢
Coffee. Black, please.
家人好吗？
So, how's the family?
很好
Good, sir.
何时可以见见莱恩医生？
When am I gonna meet the other Dr. Ryan?
- 她也很想见你  - 很好，很好
- She's dying to meet you, sir. - Good, good.
请坐
Sit down.
谢谢
Thank you.
钱还在吗？
So, the cash is still there?
什么？
Sir?
哈丁的海外户头
In Hardin's offshore accounts.
六亿五千万元
$650 million.
- 还有零钱  - 还有零钱
- And change. - And change.
我们有帐号吗？
And we have the account numbers.
有的
Yes, sir.
那么还等什么？把钱领出来吧
Well, what are we waiting for? Let's get it.
- 把钱领出来？ - 把钱领出来
- "Let's get it"? - Let's get it.
把这些钱汇回来
Let's turn this thing around.
六亿五千万加零钱
$650 million and change.
这可比政治资金多十倍
It's worth 10 times that in political capital.
怎样？
What?
哈丁和犯罪集团的勾结是个…
This connection between Hardin and the cartels is a...
推论
theory.
- 推论？  - 我的推论
- "Theory"? - A theory of mine.
这是推论？
It's a theory?
我知道钱确实存在
Well, I know the money is there
不过哈丁究竟…
but who exactly Hardin...
替谁工作，我不确定
was working for, I don't know that exactly,
我想我们必须查清楚
and I think we would have to establish that
才能动那笔钱
before we could seize the money.
那就去啊，快去查清楚
So go down there and establish it.
- 去哪？  - 哥伦比亚
- Go where? - Colombia.
谁，我吗？
Who, me?
我才丢下你短短两周
I leave you alone for two weeks,
你就惹来一身腥
and you walk straight into a big bear trap.
不懂自己在想什么
I don't know what I was thinking.
你想让总统对你刮目相看
You were thinking about impressing the President of the United States
真不是明智之举
and you shouldn't do that.
十一月
November.
- 一月  - 那是去年的
- January. - Of last year.
那里有个家伙
There's a guy down there.
至少以前是的
At least, he used to be.
他就是克拉克
Clark.
我们交情很深 是个好人
We go way back. Good man.
有麻烦，就去找他
If you hit a brick wall, look him up.
格里尔上将？
Admiral Greer?
- 化疗  - 真要命
- Chemotherapy. - Shit.
又要来了
Here we go again.
里特表现得如何？
How's Ritter behaving?
里特吗？
Ritter?
里特还是老样子，根本不鸟我
Ritter's Ritter. He's leaving me alone.
你确定？
Are you sure?
你要小心他哦！
Watch him like a hawk.
你今天感觉如何，上将？
How you feeling today, Admiral?
还好啦
Okey-dokey.
好的，我们带你去房间
All right, now, we're gonna get you in the room.
准备暖暖的毛毯
We've got some warm blankets for you.
只要在那里躺几分钟
It's just gonna take a few minutes.
我们带你去躺下来
We'll get you lying right down there,
然后带你回到舒服的房间
then we'll get you back up to your room and all comfortable.
昨天的治疗还会有点晕吗？
Still a little bit of nausea from yesterday?
变数，这是刀子，准备接受信号，结束
Variable, this is Knife. Stand by to copy. Over.
刀子，这是变数
Knife, this is Variable.
你的信号是5乘5，结束
Your signal is five-by-five. Over.
安全
Clear.
鸡在锅子里了，结束
The chicken is in the pot. Over.
- 煮了吧  - 收到
- Cook it. - Roger that.
亲爱的！
Honey?
我来不及了，拜
I'm late. Bye.
祝旅途愉快
Have a good trip.
我不想说
I'm not going to say it.
那就别说
Don't.
要小心
Be careful.
（哥伦比亚，波哥大）
当地时间是…
And local time is...
其实和华盛顿相同，早上11点16分
Well, actually, it's the same as Washington. It's 11:16 a.m.
气温是华氏69度…
Gonna be a temperature of about 69 degrees Fahrenheit...
莱恩博士！
Dr. Ryan!
缉毒署，琼·福勒探员
DEA Special Agent Jean Fowler.
- 你好吗？  - 你好，琼
- How you doing? - Hi, Jean.
- 第一次到波哥大，是吧？  - 是的
- First time in Bogota, am I right? - Yeah.
那就别站在这里等人向你开枪
Well, let's not stand out here and let somebody take a shot at you.
你才刚到耶
Hell, you just got here.
走吧，先生，我们走
Come on, sir. Let's go.
这两个是…
And these two are...
- 他们是兄弟  - 兄弟
- They're brothers. - Brothers.
别开窗，帮莱恩博士
Don't... Don't do that.
把空调开大一点
Give Dr. Ryan a little bit more air back here, please.
那是防弹玻璃
Bulletproof.
我们没照片
We don't have a picture.
他是埃斯科贝多的情报员
Escobedo's intelligence officer.
不知其名，不过确实有此人
We don't have a name either, but we know he exists.
隐形人吗？
Invisible man, huh?
手要轻轻的
Gently, gently with your hands.
路易斯，双手握好！
Luis, put your hands together!
不是！你的双手！握好！
No! Your hands! Together!
很好、很好
Good. Good.
路易斯，小心慢慢跑！
Luis, watch the canter!
现在小跑 好
Now trot. Good.
对！
Yes!
非常好！
Very good!
是的
Yes.
又失去一架飞机
We lost another plane.
现在短跑
Now go to a shorter trot.
好的
Okay.
是谁干的？
Who is doing this?
要我猜吗？
If I had to guess?
不，我不要你猜
No, that's not what I asked you, to guess.
我也会猜
I can guess.
有人跟缉毒小组告密
Someone has been talking to the drug police.
那是不可能的
Now, that's impossible.
要是有人告密，我会第一个知道
If anyone spoke to the police, I would be the first to know.
埃内斯托
Ernesto?
你认为在我把美国那家人干掉后
You think one of the others is trying to ruin me,
有人想毁了我，抢我的生意？
to steal my business, after what I did to the American?
我猜也不是你想的那样
I guess that wasn't quite the deterrent you thought it would be.
去查出是谁
Find out who it is.
你怎么看这件事，上校？
What do you make of this, Colonel?
一个机会
An opportunity.
一个大好机会
An opportunity, Sipo.
- 午安  - 午安
- Good afternoon. - Afternoon.
有留言吗？
Messages, please.
- 莱恩博士？ - 谢谢
- Dr. Ryan? - Thank you.
克拉克
Clark.
抱歉迟到了
I'm sorry I'm late.
我有十分钟
I got 10 minutes.
好的
Okay.
我确定哈丁和犯罪集团有关
I mean, I'm positive that Hardin was tied into the cartels.
那绝对是贩毒的钱
It's definitely drug money.
但你无法证明
But you can't prove it.
目前是的
So far.
介意我问你一个问题吗？
Mind if I ask you a question?
不会
No.
为什么告诉我这件事？
Why are you telling me all this?
我已经脱离这行很久了
I've been out of the game for a long time.
有人告诉我…
Oh, well, I was told that...
你在这里很吃得开
That you were wired in down here,
地缘、人脉都很广
that you knew the town, the people,
是个中好手
that you were a player.
谁告诉你的？
Who told you that?
詹姆斯·格里尔
Jim Greer.
他好吗？
How's he doing?
不太好
Well, he's not good.
他得了癌症…
It's cancer.
末期
Terminal.
他是个好人
He's a good man.
最好的
The best.
你喝咖啡吗，莱恩博士？
You a coffee drinker, Dr. Ryan?
是的，我喜欢喝咖啡
Yeah, I like coffee.
试试林度牌
Try the Lindo brand.
林度
Lindo.
我想你会喜欢
I think you'll like it.
总统先生，我有一些好消息
Mr. President, I've got some good news.
很好
Good.
哈丁在这里的合伙人，是你知道的人
Hardin's partner down here was someone you may have heard of,
就是埃内斯托·埃斯科贝多
Ernesto Escobedo.
- 埃斯科贝多  - 是哦
- Escobedo. - That figures.
这又是你的另一个推论吗，莱恩？
Now, is this another of your theories, Ryan?
不是的，这是事实
No, sir. I think we can call this one fact.
埃斯科贝多跟这里其他毒贩头子一样
Escobedo, like every other drug lord down here,
也经营合法生意
was also running legitimate businesses,
哈丁也参与这些生意
and Hardin was doing business with these businesses,
进口很多货品，包括咖啡
importing, among other things, coffee,
这件事看来似乎没什么
which in and of itself means nothing,
但他对咖啡出的价太高
but he was paying a little bit too much for this coffee.
每磅要六千两百元
$6,200 a pound,
我没算错的话
if my arithmetic is correct.
好贵的咖啡
Well, that's expensive coffee.
是的，我同意
Yes, sir. I'd have to agree.
好了，这是好消息
Well, this is good news.
就这样
I think this does it.
总统
Sir?
我还有另一个不太好的消息
I also have some other news which is not so good.
哦，老天
Oh, God.
缉毒署认为…
DEA here feels that the...
哥伦比亚政府会想要…
Colombian government would want the...
没收这笔钱或其中一大部分的钱
seized funds or at least a large portion of them.
这是我们的钱
Well, this is our money.
这是我们的钱，我们发现的
This is our money. We found it.
我们可以试着跟他们谈
We could try telling them that.
试？直接告诉他们
"Try"? Tell them.
或是不告诉他们 随便啦
Or don't tell them. I don't care.
总统，恕我…
Sir, with all due respect...
直接告诉他们 这是我们的钱
This is our money. Just tell them that.
我不知道该怎么说 也不知道从何说起
I wouldn't know what to say. I wouldn't know where to start.
我不是谈判专家
I'm not a negotiator.
你不是认识他们政府的人吗？
Don't you know someone in their government?
我曾跟他们的司法部长一起求学
I went to school with their attorney general.
雅各布斯会去 他会负责谈判
Jacobs will come down. He'll take care of it. He'll negotiate.
- 好的  - 这是我们的钱
- Yes, sir. - This is our money.
谢…
Thank...
谢谢你
Thank you.
我讨厌这工作
I hate this job.
小心前面！
Eyes up!
爆破小组，快往前！
Demo team, up!
准备安装！
Device set!
炸弹进洞！
Fire in the hole!
快走！快走！快离开！
Let's go! Let's go! Move out!
走！走！走！
Go! Go! Go! Go!
趴下！趴下！
Down! Down!
干这件事的人死定了
Whoever did this is dead.
敢对我干这件事的人死定了！
Whoever did this to me is dead!
听到没？！
Do you hear me?
有没有听到我的话？！
Are you listening to me?
到飞机上再讨论一遍
We'll go over it in the plane again.
雅各布斯先生，离开前能不能签一下这些文件？
Mr. Jacobs, could you sign these before you leave?
- 利兹，你跟我妻子说了吗？  - 是的
- Liz, did you speak to my wife? - Yes.
莫伊拉，你明天要不要请个病假？
Moira, why don't you call in sick tomorrow?
还有后天
And the next day.
我不会说出去的
I won't tell anybody.
就算你不在，工作也不会少
Just because you're not here doesn't mean there's nothing to do.
你的行程表
Your itinerary.
连这种事也要跟我争论吗？
You're gonna argue with me about this?
你工作太辛苦了
You work too hard.
再见
Adios.
祝愉快
Have a good time.
雅各布斯局长办公室
Director Jacobs' office.
是的，你好
Oh, yes. Hold on.
好的
All right.
我有初步的行程表
I do have a tentative schedule...
（委内瑞拉，麦格提亚）
请接罗伯托·兰达，我是莫伊拉·沃夫森
Roberto Landa, please. This is Moira Wolfson.
请稍等，沃夫森小姐 我看看能不能找到他
One moment, please, Ms. Wolfson. I'll see if I can find him.
我想他在工厂某处
I think he's on the factory floor someplace.
请稍等
Hold on, please.
- 什么事？  - 莫伊拉·沃夫森来电
- Yes? - A Moira Wolfson is calling.
我跟她说你在工厂
I told her you were on the factory floor.
好的
Okay.
请讲吧
Go ahead.
莫伊拉！
Moira!
你这几天有空吗？
You free in the next couple of days?
这几天吗？
The next couple of days?
我有空
I am.
我老板出国了
My boss is leaving the country.
我待会儿回你电话？
Can I call you later?
好的，打到我家，拜
All right. Call me at home. Bye.
好的
Okay.
午安
Good afternoon.
午安，总统先生
Good afternoon, Mr. President.
打击毒贩方面有好消息
Good news in the fight against drugs.
我很高兴在此宣布，根据司法部的调查
I wish to announce that an investigation by the Department of Justice
已查获数个银行帐户
has identified several bank accounts
卢森堡及开曼群岛
from Luxembourg to the Cayman Islands
作为毒贩洗钱之用
used for laundering drug money...
金额空前庞大
on an unprecedented scale.
在五国政府合作下
In cooperation with five foreign governments,
我们已采取必要行动没收这笔赃款
we have taken the necessary steps to seize those funds,
总金额逾六亿五千万元
which amount to over $650 million.
该死
Shit.
并且，查封二十间房地产合资公司
Also, to seize 20 real estate joint venture investments
在美国境内的
here in the United States,
这些公司主要用来洗黑钱
which were the primary agencies in the laundering operations.
- 总统先生！  - 马丁
- Mr. President! - Martin.
总统先生，你刚说六亿五千万元吗？
Mr. President, you did say $650 million?
没错，六亿五千万加零钱
That's right. It is $650 million and change.
他们偷我的钱！
They're stealing my money!
- 伊莉莎白？  - 我们有多少胜算？
- Elizabeth. - What's our take?
- 我没听清楚  - 我们有多少胜算？
- I'm sorry? - What's our take?
我们的胜算 此刻很难说
Our take. It's hard to say at the moment.
- 才不是  - 很难说…
- No, it isn't. - It's hard to describe...
你偷我的钱，那是我赚的，你偷我的钱！
You're stealing my money. I made it and you're stealing it!
- 总统先生  - 什么？
- Mr. President. - Yeah?
我们可不可以请联邦调查局局长雅各布斯说明这件事？
Can we speak with FBI Director Jacobs about this matter?
雅各布斯局长目前无法回应
Director Jacobs is not available for comment.
有人要付出代价
Someone will die for this.
他亲自参与这项调查
He's personally involved in this investigation.
他和他的小组此刻无法分身
As you can imagine, he and his team are pretty busy at the moment.
（林度咖啡）
不，不
No, no.
必须避开这条街
This avenue has to be avoided.
他们从机场来…
They'll be coming from the airport...
沿厄尔多拉多大道
up Avenida Aeropuerto El Dorado
到阿美利亚大道
all the way to Gran America.
圣大非是我们的据点
Santa Fe's our spot.
我很想留在这里看好戏
As much as I would love to be here for this,
但我得到华盛顿办点事
I have to take care of some business in Washington,
有些事要做了结
tying up some loose ends.
喂，别挂断！别挂断！
Hello. Don't hang up! Don't hang up!
拜
Bye.
喂？
Hello?
答录机还开着，莫伊拉
The machine is still on, Moira.
（司法部，联邦调查局）
埃米尔，幸会
Emile. Good to see you.
谢谢，安迪，幸会
Thank you, Andy. Good to see you.
穆雷探员、费里斯大使
Agent Murray, Ambassador Ferris.
- 你好  - 大使
- How are you? - Ambassador.
嗨，真高兴看到你 这是最新资料
Hi, good to see you. This will bring you up to date.
太好了
Oh, terrific.
好了，走吧
All right. Let's go.
食物好吃吗？
So how's the food?
就像墨西哥料理
It's like Mexican food.
- 我讨厌墨西哥料理  - 你讨厌墨西哥料理
- I hate Mexican food. - You hate Mexican food.
我秘书所知道的美国
The only thing my secretary knows about America
全都是从旅游手册及杂志看来的
is what she reads in travel brochures and People magazine.
这里好吗？
How's the place?
进来不就知道了
Come inside and find out.
好的
Okay.
这里…糟透了
It's awful.
是吗？
Isn't it?
我想你没喝这里的水
So I take it you shouldn't drink the water.
房间里有供应水，但我没喝
Well, they put water in your room, but I wouldn't trust it.
我还是瓶装矿泉水
I'd stick with the bottled stuff.
那你怎么刷牙？
So what do you brush your teeth with?
用瓶装矿泉水
Use the bottled water,
不然就得一直躺在医院里
or you'll be in the can all the time you're here.
持枪抢劫案和政府有关？
Our holdup was a government connection?
大有关系，不用怀疑
Yeah, yeah, that's the big connection. No doubt.
怎么回事？
What the hell?
我的天！
- Jesus! - Oh, my God!
后退！后退！
Back up! Back up!
快点！跟上！
Move it! Step on it!
趴下！趴下！
Stay down, boss! Stay down!
- 趴下！  - 该死！
- Stay down! - Damn it!
小心！
Watch out!
该死！该死！后退！后退！
Damn it! Damn it! Back up! Back up!
快走！快走！快出去！
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
- 冷静点，安迪  - 继续走！
- Take it easy, Andy. - We've got to keep moving!
快走，杰克！
Go, Jack!
快走，杰克！走啊！
Come on, Jack! Go!
快走，杰克！
Come on, let's go, Jack!
炸弹来了！
Incoming!
绕过去！
Get around it!
你后面！
Behind you!
丹恩！
Dan!
丹恩、丹恩！
Dan. Dan!
不能留在这里！
We can't stay here!
车子还能开吗？
The car, is it running?
可以！
It's running!
浓烟可以当掩护 这是唯一的机会
The smoke will give us cover. It's our only chance.
我背他
I got him.
冲向驾驶座
Make for the driver's side.
预备…走！
Ready? Go!
进去！
Get in!
快走！快走！
Go! Go!
打扫房间
Housekeeping.
打扰了，夫人
Excuse me, ma'am.
联邦调查局局长埃米尔·雅各布斯…
FBI director Emile Jacobs...
- 有电话找莱恩医生  - 请等一下，医生
- You have a call for Dr. Ryan? - Just a moment, Doctor.
…今天在波哥大街头遇难
...automatic weapons in the streets of Bogota today.
请把莱恩博士的电话转到451
Please transfer Dr. Ryan's call to 451.
共有十人死亡，八人受伤
Ten members of the escort party were also killed and eight wounded.
其中五名死者确认是贴身护卫…
Five of the dead have been identified as security personnel attached to the...
凯西
Cathy.
别跟我说你也在场
Don't tell me you're in this thing.
我就在现场
I'm right in the middle of it.
亲爱的，丹恩死了
Honey, Dan was killed.
丹恩·穆雷
Dan Murray.
我近在咫尺却束手无策
I was 10 feet away. There was nothing I could do.
我要回家了
I'm coming home.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
我爱你
I love you.
我以为没人知道他去那里
I thought his going down there was a secret.
是的
It was.
那么我不明白
Then I don't get it.
怎么会这样？
What happened?
没人知道
Nobody knows.
这些人怎么这么蠢？
How stupid are these people?
他们认为可以为所欲为
They believe they can do anything.
知道吗？他们错了
You know what? They're wrong.
- 是，总统  - 大错特错
- Yes, sir. - They're wrong.
他们公然挑战
They've directly challenged
美国政府的公权力
the sovereign power of the United States.
不能再通讯息了
No more sending messages.
不管电话有没有响，他要他们全面监控
He wants them to get the message whether the phone rings or not.
他下的令吗？
Those are his words?
听来像吗？
Do they sound like his words?
他总是避免直接了当地把话说明
He can't be clear when clarity is exactly what he wants to avoid.
他真正的意思是采取强硬手段
What he means is the gloves come off.
对
Yeah.
我告诉你
I'm telling you,
我和这件事无关
I had nothing to do with it.
不是我干的
I didn't.
真希望是我，他们活该
I wish I had done it. They deserve it.
但不是我干的
But it wasn't me.
那么是谁干的？
Who did, then?
你总是没答案
You know, you have no answers.
你跟卡斯特罗是这样合作的吗？没答案？
Is this the way it was with Castro? No answers?
你不想听到答案
You don't want to hear an answer.
我想
Yes, I do.
这件事看起来像是你干的
It was done to look like you did it,
有人想栽赃
by one of the others,
如你所怀疑的
as you suspected.
一定是最恨你的朋友
It's always a friend who hates you most.
给我电话
Give me the phone.
- 我是罗杰斯  - 是你干的吗？
- Rojas. - Did you do this thing?
是我干的吗？
Did I do this thing?
你打来就是要问我，是我干的吗？
Are you calling to ask me if I did this thing?
你做事不找人商量
You don't consult with us.
害我们身陷危机…
You put us in danger.
（亚利桑那州，华丘卡堡）
现在还很狂妄地要我相信不是你干的？
And now you have the arrogance to want me to believe that it wasn't you?
不是我干的，恩里克
It wasn't, Enrique.
你惹到美国人了，他们会来找大家算帐
You have invited the Americans to retaliate against all of us.
我发誓，我和这件事无关
I swear. I had nothing to do with it.
完全无关！
Nothing!
你凭什么叫我相信你的一派胡言？
Why do you expect me to listen to you when you're lying to me?
- 再见，埃内斯托  - 不、不、不！
- Goodbye, Ernesto. - No, no, no!
别挂断
Don't hang up.
- 我们必须见个面  - 何时？
- We must have a meeting. - When?
愈快愈好，把这件事说清楚
As soon as possible, to straighten this thing out.
明天晚上
Tomorrow night.
不，我不是告诉你，我是要求你！
No, I am not telling you. I am asking you!
（拦截345）明天晚上见个面好吗？
May we please have a meeting tomorrow night?
- 明天晚上  - 谢谢你
- Tomorrow afternoon. - Thank you.
- 他吓到了  - 应该的
- He's scared. - He should be.
我不知道你跟他说了什么，不过说得好
I don't know what you said to him but it was right.
很怪吧？
Strange, don't you think?
雅各布斯和他的秘书同一天遇害
Jacobs and his secretary getting killed on the same day.
他不是秘书
He wasn't a secretary.
他是助手，负责维安的
He was an assistant, a member of the security detail.
谁？
Who?
我不记得他的名字
I don't remember his name.
我说的是莫伊拉
I'm talking about Moira.
什么？
What?
莫伊拉 你记得的，雅各布斯的秘书
Moira. You remember. Jacobs' secretary.
我知道莫伊拉
I know Moira, honey.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
她说他是拉丁版的杰克·莱恩
She said he was the "Latin Jack Ryan."
是吗？
He was? I mean...
她是那么说的
Yeah, that's what she called him.
我知道
I know.
重点是他是拉丁人
The point is he's Latin,
让我不禁怀疑她的死和雅各布斯有关
which, in my mind, connects her death and Jacobs' beyond the mere fact
因为他们俩一起工作
that they worked together.
你见过跟这两起命案有关的嫌犯？
You saw somebody you think is responsible for both killings?
- 是的  - 是的
- Yes. - Yes.
她见过
She did.
莫伊拉，是妈妈，亲爱的…
Hi, Moira, it's Mom. Honey...
她见过
She did.
我从很远的地方看到他的背影
I saw him from a distance, from behind.
身高中等、体形中等吗？
Medium height, medium build, et cetera?
可以让我看看吗？
You mind if I look at these?
度假小屋的人那么形容吗？
Is that what the people from the cabin said?
是的
Yeah.
你有查过委内瑞拉这几通电话吗？
Did you check out these calls to Venezuela?
查无此电话
Disconnected.
好吧
Okay.
- 所以没线索？  - 我有很多线索
- So, you have no leads, huh? - I have a lot of leads.
登记住房的假名字
I have a fictitious name on a register.
盗用的信用卡帐号
I have a stolen, phoned-in credit card number.
还有两名目击证人
I have two eyewitnesses,
其中一名曾在房里看到嫌犯，但没看清楚
one of whom was in the room who saw a guy but really didn't see him.
慢点，打断一下
Wait, wait, wait. Excuse me.
那段留言可以再播一次吗？
Could you play that again?
好的，长官
Yes, sir.
答录机还开着，莫伊拉
The machine is still on, Moira.
你有嫌犯声音的录音…
You have a recording of the killer's voice.
…也许吧
Maybe.
杰克，我们有新发现
Jack, I think we got something here.
这是答录机的
This is from the answering machine,
这是昨天录的
and this was recorded yesterday.
- 我播给你听  - 好的
- I'll play it for you. - Okay.
答录机还开着，莫伊拉
The machine is still on, Moira.
好的
All right.
还有…
And...
- 他吓到了  - 应该的
- He's scared. - He should be.
我不知道你跟他说什么，不过说得好
I don't know what you said to him but it was right.
寇特，做个比对
Kirk, run a match on that for me.
答录机还开着，莫伊拉
The machine is still on, Moira.
他是古巴人
He's Cuban,
35到45岁
35 to 45,
在美国受教育
educated in the United States,
美国东部
Eastern United States.
是同一个声音
That's the voice. Same voice.
- 你确定？  - 是的
- You're sure? - Yeah.
多确定？
How sure?
（可能性）
九成
90%.
我要名字
I need a name.
这可是有成千上万个声音
You're talking about hundreds of thousands of voices.
我知道，我要名字，而且要快
Yeah, yeah, I know. Find me the name and I mean quick.
（巴拿马湾）
300号准备
300 is topside.
Flight ops 1915 to 2300.
Spate flight ops until 1800.
101号五分钟后起飞
101 at ready 5.
302号在甲板待命
302 is on deck.
目标锁定
Target is set.
贺特！
Hector!
恩里克！
Enrique!
真高兴见到你！
Good to see you!
好不容易才能聚会
It was not easy for us.
恩里克，你好
Enrique, how are you?
罗杰斯…
Rojas.
迪亚兹…
Diaz.
这是什么东东？
Oh, what the hell is this?
What the hell is this?
我的新玩具，喜欢吗？
My new toy. Like it?
看到没？
You see this?
那是你的新目标，除非你嫌它不够大
That's your new target, unless it's not big enough.
变数，这是懒犀牛，听到吗？结束
Variable, this is Easy Rhino. Do you copy? Over.
又大又清楚，懒犀牛
Loud and clear, Easy Rhino.
有目标吗？结束
Do we have a gig? Over.
有的
That's a rog.
目标锁定
Target is lit.
开始奏乐
Start the music.
准备攻击
Into attack.
导弹待命
Pickle is hot.
目标锁定
Target is acquired and lit.
发射！
Coming down.
费南多兹…
Fernandez.
维加…
Vega.
看来全到齐了
Looks like a full house.
该死！他怎么不把路修好？
Damn it! Why doesn't he fix this road?
可恶！
Shit.
还以为全到齐了
I thought we had everybody.
继续瞄准目标
Keep the target painted.
长官
Sir.
砰！
Boom.
我的天啊
Mother of God.
错误可能性为零
Circular error probability zero.
一弹命中，祝你有个愉快的一天
Impact with high-order detonation. Have a nice day.
这个人完全疯了
The man is completely out of control.
他没有…
He has no...
这个人完全疯了
The man is completely out of control.
完全疯了
Completely out of control.
（吻合：柯特斯、费里斯）
他姓柯特斯
His name is Cortez.
费里斯·柯特斯
Felix Cortez.
本来是古巴情报局上校
He was a colonel in Cuba's intelligence service
直到几年前突然消失
until a few years ago. Disappeared.
转而替波多黎各的
He turned up working for the Macheteros.
恐怖分子工作
It's a terrorist group in Puerto Rico.
然后再度消失 直到昨天
Disappeared again. Then yesterday,
我们录到他和卡里集团的人通话
we taped him talking to a Cali cartel subject.
我会把他的资料传给你
Look, I'll fax you what I have on him.
他若现身，就替我逮捕他，好吗？
If he shows up, pick him up for me, will you?
- 你知道我不能那么做  - 不，我不是说你
- You know I can't do that. - No, no, no, I don't mean you.
我是说哥伦比亚警方
I mean the police, the Colombians.
哥伦比亚警方
The Colombian police,
杰克，不会招惹犯罪集团的人
Jack, do not pick up members of the cartel.
除非他们自投罗网
I mean, unless they've got some kind of a death wish.
我是说你也遇过啊
I mean, you've been down here.
等我一下
Wait a minute.
哦，老天
Oh, Jesus.
杰克，大事不妙了
Jack, something's happened here.
至少30人被杀，包括妇女和儿童
At least 30 people were killed, including women and children.
哥伦比亚警方发现炸弹是在
Colombian police report that the bomb exploded
罗杰斯同伙所有的一辆车里爆炸的
in a car belonging to one of Rojas' associates.
杰克？杰克？
Jack! Jack!
- 你在看电视吗？  - 是啊
- Yeah, are you watching this? - Yeah.
- 这是刚发生的吗？  - 刚发生
- This just happen? - Just now.
…卡里集团
...counsel of the Cali cocaine cartel
哥伦比亚最有名的企业家之一
and is one of Colombia's best-known businessmen.
把这个人的资料传来
Look, send me all the stuff
我们会派人跟踪他
and we'll put a tail on him if we spot him.
如果他还活着，我要挂电话了
If he's still alive. I got to go.
最近一连串的神秘爆炸案
This blast is the latest in a series of mysterious explosions.
如果他还活着，我要挂电话了
If he's still alive. I got to go.
最近一连串的神秘爆炸案
This blast is the latest in a series of mysterious explosions.
警方声明暴力…
The cops claim the violence is part of a bitter...
你保证过会做得很漂亮
You said it was going to be a surgical strike.
是很漂亮
It was. It was perfect.
电视台刚刚报导他们抱出一名小孩
That's a kid they just brought out, on NBC.
你当初说 “采强硬手段，痛宰他们”
"Take the gloves off. Hurt them." That's what you said.
我知道我当初怎么说
I know what I said, Bobby.
现在改变心意了？有点太迟了吧
Are you changing your mind now? It's a little late for that.
不，我没改变心意
No, I'm not changing my mind.
（卡里市爆炸案）
我没料到会…伤及无辜
I hadn't counted on this kind of collateral damage,
他也没料到
and neither did he.
我会给它合理化
It'll be interpreted just like I said it would,
汽车炸弹了结毒枭的对立
rivalry that ended in the blast of a car bomb.
晚安
Good night.
消息指出哥伦比亚反毒单位
The terror campaign indicates a new guerrilla offensive
派出游击兵对抗贩毒集团
against the cartels by anti-drug units of the Colombian...
（简报 卡里市汽车炸弹攻击案）
早安，萝丝，报告完成了？
Good morning, Rose. You finish the report?
- 刚出炉  - 谢了
- Hot off the press. - Thanks.
遇害者的姓名有没有可能是假名？
Any chances any of these bombing victims' names are aliases?
不可能 所有身分都查证过了
No. All IDs have been confirmed.
你想找谁？
Who were you hoping for?
他不在名单里 柯特斯不在名单里
He's not here, he's not here. Cortez.
他不在名单里
He's not here.
行动小组为什么要副本？
Why was Operations copied on this?
里特要求的
Ritter requested it.
里特？
Ritter, huh?
你今天很漂亮
You look very nice today.
谢谢
Thank you.
汽车炸弹
Car bomb.
汽车炸弹点燃会怎样？
What happens when a car bomb goes off?
会炸开
It explodes.
对，会向外炸开
Right. It blows up and out.
导弹呢？
And a missile?
- 像这种比较深的坑洞？  - 那是导弹的特性
- This deep a crater? - That's characteristic.
现在看看卫星图片
Okay, bring up the satellite photo.
是HMX和TNT
HMX and TNT
用七比三的比例混合
which when you mix it 70-30,
能制造出所谓的奥托尔化合物
you get a compound called Octol.
在后车箱放足够的量
Put enough explosives in the back of a car
就会炸出那么大的坑洞
and you'll get a crater that big.
它很稳定
It's very stable,
- 对，但车子还会在里头吗？ - 很昂贵…
- Yeah, but would it still be in it? - very expensive...
管它什么车的，它还会在坑洞里头吗？
The car, the truck, whatever, would it still be in the crater?
- 爆炸威力强大  - 我想车子会炸成碎片
- Very violent. - I think it would be blown to bits.
这边到处都会有它的碎片
There'd be pieces of it all around there.
哪里生产奥托尔？
And where is Octol made?
很多地方都有
Lots of places.
欧洲
Europe,
美国
the US.
但没人使用
But nobody uses it.
除了军方没人负担得起
Nobody can afford it except the military.
空中轰炸做得到
An aerial bomb would do that,
不过这不是空中轰炸
but that's not an aerial bomb.
- 不是吗？  - 不是
- It's not? - No.
所有东西都有纤维残留物
There is also a cellulose residue on everything.
这里和这里应该都要有炸弹碎片
There should be shrapnel here and here...
可是却没有
but there isn't.
没有炸弹碎片
No bomb fragments.
（国际防御指南 部队武器大全）
（化合军用武器）
（纤维料雷射导弹）
“纤维料雷射导弹”
"Cellulose encased laser-guided bomb."
文件
Paper.
美国人做的
The Americans are here.
我们有共同点
We have something in common.
我们不能执行政策
Neither of us can implement policy
至少没有雇主的默许
without at least tacit authorization from our employer.
另外还有一个共同点
We have something else in common.
我们俩都知道美军在哥伦比亚
We both know there are American troops in Colombia
展开一场非法之战
fighting an illegal war.
星期三我会在巴拿马市
I will be staying at the Hotel Paloma de Oro
派洛玛欧洛饭店
in Panama City on Wednesday.
我提议见个面
I suggest we meet.
小六，我是小尖，结束
Six, this is Point. Over.
我是小六
Six here.
毒品在这里，数量很多
The stuff's here and there's a lot of it.
还有一百到一百五十名
I'm also looking at 100 to 150 men,
持枪的人，好像在等什么
armed, waiting around for something.
结束
Over.
哥伦比亚军吗？结束
Colombian Army? Over.
不是，看来像佣兵
Negative. They look like mercenaries.
结束
Over.
好的
All right.
撤退，终止任务
Get on back here. Abort mission.
重复，终止任务，通话结束
I say again, abort mission. Out.
一百五十名持枪的人？
150 armed men, huh?
（最高机密）
麻烦双手举高
Raise your arms, please.
谢谢你这么快回覆
Thank you for responding to my note so promptly.
你应该知道我跟雅各布斯先生的死无关
You should know that I had nothing to do with the death of Mr. Jacobs.
这是疯子所为
It was an act of madness,
不过是我的众多雇主里最疯狂的一个
but a typical one from the men I work for.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
跟你一样，矿泉水
Same as you. Mineral water.
我们都同意只要美国人有毒品的需求
Can we agree that as long as Americans demand drugs,
就会有人想卖吧？
someone will supply them?
听好，非必要的话，我不想在此久留
Look, I don't want to be here any longer than I have to.
你在传真函里提到非法之战
You said something in your fax about a gang war.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
你和我要的都一样
That you and I want the same thing.
一样吗？
"The same thing." Really?
只是目前，全都是你在做
Only so far, you've done all the work.
你解决了那几条小鱼
You've taken care of the little fish.
我来解决漏网那条大鱼
I will take care of the one that got away.
一旦铲除了埃斯科贝多
Once Escobedo is gone,
我就可以顺理成章地帮你
I will be in the position to help you.
你要帮我？
You want to help me, huh?
帮你的国家、你的人民
Your country, your people.
藉由重新协定毒品交易
By restructuring the drug trade,
将它规则化
by regulating it.
如果我跟你保证
What would you say if I promised you
可卡因输入美国的量减半呢？
I will reduce the cocaine shipments to your country by half?
我想你一定吸毒吸到头壳坏了
I'd say you've been using too much of your product.
我也可以跟你保证常常破获大宗案件
I can also promise you regular quotas on major arrests
你的警方可以立功
that your police can take credit for.
想像一下：破案率大增
Imagine that, dramatic seizures,
毒品锐减，再也没有无谓的暴力事件
drastic reductions, no more senseless violence.
你会取得胜利
You'll have your victory.
代价是什么？
In return for what?
我也需要功绩
Well, I also need a victory
才能在残余的犯罪集团里建立我的地位
to establish my position with what is left of the cartel
如此才能帮你
so I can help you.
我必须打败那些到处乱炸的士兵
I need to defeat those soldiers blowing up everything they see.
给我他们的位置图
Give me maps of their locations.
切断他们的通讯
Cut off their communications.
缉毒署把监控录音带寄过来
DEA is sending the audio surveillance tape.
我还没收到
I haven't got it yet.
你可知道躺在这里…
You know what you think about
会有什么想法吗？
when you're lying here?
知道自己快死了，心里想…
You know you're gonna die, and you think
没关系的
that's all right.
你已经活够久了
You lived a long time.
你有爱你的家人
You had a family that loved you.
也有一份自以为能改变一切的工作
You had a job that you thought made a difference,
以为这是很光荣的…
that you thought was honorable.
…结果却看到这些
And then you see this.
我怕再追查下去
I'm afraid if I dig any deeper,
没有人会喜欢我发现的真相
no one's gonna like what I find.
你发过誓…
You took an oath,
…如果你记得…
if you recall,
就在你第一天来替我工作的时候
when you first came to work for me,
我不是指
and I don't mean to the National Security Advisor
美国国家安全顾问
of the United States.
我是指他的老板
I mean to his boss.
我也不是指总统
And I don't mean the President.
你对他的老板…
You gave your word to
发过誓
his boss.
你对美国人民发过誓
You gave your word to the people of the United States.
发过誓就要实现
Your word is who you are.
你还带了什么？
What else you got there?
我带了几本新杂志给你
I brought you some new magazines.
东帝汶的局势似乎稳定下来了
...and the situation in East Timor seems to have stabilized during the day.
很好
Good.
就这样吗？
Is that it?
还有一件事
Except for the other thing.
我们做得很成功，也看到具体成果
We've accomplished a lot. We're seeing tangible results.
毒品运量减少
Drug shipments are down.
黑市价格上升
Price on the street is rising.
看来政府的行动是正确的
Perception is that the administration is doing something right.
坏消息呢？
What's the bad news?
我担心最近这起
I'm concerned about this latest incident,
汽车炸弹案，紧接着雅各布斯遇刺案发生
the car bomb coming so soon after Jacobs' assassination.
让记者有文章可做
It's just the kind of thing reporters live for.
他们最爱把事件做连结
They'd love to try to make a connection.
你认为他们会
And you think they will.
我认为是该做个了断了
I think it's time the whole thing went away.
如果你是这么想的话
If that's what you think.
我是这么想
I think so.
那么就做个了断吧
Then it should go away.
当作从没发生过
It never happened.
是的，总统
Yes, sir.
是有可能
Well, I mean, it's possible.
如果能告诉我
It would be a lot easier
你要我入侵哪个系统，会比较简单点
if you told me whose system you wanted me to break into.
- 早安，莱恩博士  - 早安
- Good morning, Dr. Ryan. - Morning.
这不光是生日日期而已
We're way beyond birthdays now.
我必须写个特别的程式
I'm gonna have to write a special program here.
好的
Right.
好了，宝贝，开始工作吧
Okay, sweetheart, let's get to work.
很好
Fine. Good.
太好了！
Yes!
开始罗
Here we go.
（422号使用者登入）
“互惠行动”那是什么？
"Reciprocity." What's that?
喂
Yeah.
我忘了告诉你
I forgot to tell you.
取得密码后
After you get the code,
等他登出系统，你再登入
wait until he's off his system before you log on
不然他会发现你入侵
because he will know it when you do.
老天，太迟了
Jesus, Petey, it's too late.
哦，我的天
Oh, my God.
（小型步兵团 突袭哥伦比亚）
（人员伤亡）
（歼灭）
（删除）
（删除档案名称：互惠01）
（发文者：卡特）
卡特
Cutter.
（档案已删除）
喂
Yeah.
巴伯，我是杰克·莱恩
Bob, Jack Ryan here.
早安，杰克
Good morning, Jack.
早安，我只是在想
Morning. Listen, I was just thinking,
我们刚开始对彼此印象不好
maybe we got off to a bad start here.
既然要在这里合作
We're going to be working together here.
或许该花点时间多多了解彼此
Maybe we should spend some time. Get to know each other a little better.
你打网球吗？
You play tennis?
网球，你打网球吗？
Tennis. You play tennis?
有、有，我打网球
Yeah, yeah, I play tennis.
找个时间一起打吧？
Well, how about we get together sometime?
也许下周，来上班之前
Next week maybe. Hour before we start work or something.
（422号使用者登入）
（档案已删除）
- 杰克  - 是的
- Jack. - Yeah.
窃取电脑资料是很严重的犯罪行为
Computer theft is a serious crime.
你这混蛋
Shit.
违反美国宪法也是
So are crimes against the Constitution.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
（隐瞒国会）
（删除档案名称：互惠02）
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
快点
Come on.
快点、快点
Come on. Come on. Come on.
（隐藏数据）
（主旨：克拉克）
克拉克
Clark.
可恶
Shit.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
（删除所有档案）
是的
Yup.
（删除所有互惠行动档案）
（列印荧幕）
（现在列印第一页）
（档案名称：克拉克资料档）
去坐牢吧，伙伴
You're going to jail, pal.
那是什么？
What is that?
你以为你发现什么？
What do you think you have there?
你犯了法
You broke the law.
你真是个童子军
You are such a Boy Scout.
看看你
Look at you.
你以为凡事只有黑与白
You see everything in black and white.
不、不、不 不是黑与白，里特
No, no, no. Not black and white, Ritter.
是对与错！
Right and wrong!
看吧？你又来了
You see? There you go again.
为什么把我摒除在外？
Why was I kept out of it?
你没有被摒除在外 你身陷其中
You weren't kept out of it. You're neck-deep in it.
你之前去了国会争取拨款
You went before Congress and you got the money for it.
还在国会面前撒谎…
You went before Congress and you lied...
我没对国会撒谎！
I never lied to Congress!
你说过，“提供并建议”
You said, "Supply and advise."
你跟他们说不会派兵 结果有派兵，杰克
You told them no troops. There are troops, Jack.
我并不知情 你明知道我不知情
I didn't know that. You know I didn't know that.
不，“我没有印象”
No. "I have no recollection of that."
这句话是你该学的
That's the term you have to learn.
谁授权的？
Who authorized this?
我相信他们会问你
I'm sure they'll ask you that.
谁授权的？
Who authorized this?
我没有印象，参议员
I have no recollection, Senator.
我没有参与这件事
I did not sign up for this.
这是某人该死的政治技俩
This is somebody's bullshit political agenda.
谁授权的？卡特吗？
Who authorized this? Cutter?
没有人批准，卡特什么屁也不敢放
Cutter couldn't tie his shoes without permission.
我要是出事，我会拖你下水
If I go down, you're going with me.
又错了
Wrong again.
我有一份签了名的“出狱许可证”
I have an autographed "Get out of jail free" card.
“总统
"The President...
授权中情局副局长罗伯特·里特
authorizes the Deputy Director, CIA, Robert Ritter,
执行互惠行动
"to conduct Operation Reciprocity,
指挥该行动所有必要的支援
"including all support necessary to such activity.
此项行动对于美国
"This operation is deemed important
国家安全极为重要”
"to the national security of the United States."
诸如此类的
Et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
你没有这个吧，杰克？
You don't have one of these, do you, Jack?
灰色！
Gray!
世界是灰色的，杰克！
The world is gray, Jack!
有没有什么点子能帮我脱身？
Got any idea how I'm gonna get out of this mess?
完全没有
Absolutely none.
喂
Yeah.
是他
This is he.
什么时候？
When?
詹姆斯吗？
James?
谢谢你
Thank you.
詹姆斯·格里尔上将
Admiral James Greer
将他的一生奉献给国家和家人
devoted his life to his country and his family,
无私地贡献其智慧与爱
giving selflessly of both his wisdom and his love.
他为国家效命逾五十年
He served his country for more than 50 years,
十七岁加入海军
enlisting in the Navy at 17,
在军校毕业
graduating from the Academy,
获得三星勋章殊荣
achieving three stars for his flag.
他在国家动荡时期执行了多起任务
He lived through tumultuous events in his country's life.
他卖命效忠
He participated in them.
清楚地向所有人证明…
He made them clearer to the rest of us...
他的学识、忠诚
with his knowledge, his honesty,
正直与勇气
his integrity and his courage.
我没看到他们，但我知道他们在下面那里
I can't see them but I know they're down there,
离你的位置往东五公里
five kilometers due east from your position.
继续往前推进，我们来围剿他们
Keep pushing forward. We'll trap them.
他从没妄想自己一个人
Never, though, was he deluded into thinking that one man
解决世间疾苦
could solve the ills of the world.
总是当一名士兵
Always the soldier,
踏遍南太平洋战场
on the battlefields of the South Pacific,
韩国、越南和华盛顿
Korea, Vietnam and Washington,
他奋力坚守…
he fought as part of a unit...
维持信念…
to preserve the ideals...
刀子，这是变数，结束
Knife, this is Variable. Over.
…他的国家
...of his nation.
刀子，这是变数，结束
Knife, this is Variable. Over.
我们把我们朋友的身躯托付给土地
To the refuge of the earth, we entrust our friend's body.
把他的灵魂托付给在天上眷顾世人的上帝
To the protection of our God in Heaven, we entrust his soul.
他的精神与做人原则
To ourselves, we entrust his spirit
与我们同在
and the principles he lived by.
我们会怀念你的，詹姆斯
We're gonna miss you, James.
掩护我！
Cover me!
我会赶上你们！
I'll show you...
变数，这是刀子，结束
Variable, this is Knife! Over!
变数，这是刀子
Variable, this is Knife.
我收不到信号，但我们遭受重击
I am not receiving but I said, we are under heavy attack.
需要空中支援，结束
We need air support. Over.
快！快！快！
Go! Go! Go!
变数，这是刀子
Variable, this is Knife. Over.
变换频道
- Switch. - Switch.
变数，这是刀子！你到底在哪里？！
Variable, this is Knife! Where the hell are you?
预备…
Present...
敬礼！
arms!
我代表感恩的人民
On behalf of a grateful nation,
表达我们的哀悼
our condolences.
他是个伟大的爱国者
He was a very great patriot.
谢谢你
Thank you.
预备
Ready.
列队，瞄准，射击！
Squad, aim, pull!
- 喂  - 琼·福勒要找莱恩博士
- Hello. - Jean Fowler for Dr. Jack Ryan.
我就是
This is he.
- 杰克？  - 哈罗，琼
- Jack? - Hello, Jean, what...
- 你一定要听听这个  - 好的
- You got to hear this. - Okay.
我今天早上在通讯频道上听到的
Picked it up this morning on itinerant frequencies.
变数，这是刀子
Variable, this is Knife.
我收不到讯号，但我们遭受重击
I am not receiving but I said, we are under heavy attack.
需要空中支援，结束！
We need air support. Over.
变数，这是刀子，你到底在哪里？！
Variable, this is Knife! Where the hell are you?
杰克，你要我怎么处理？
Jack, what do you want me to do with this?
拷贝一份，琼
Make a copy, Jean.
拷贝十份
Make 10 copies.
尽快寄给我，谢谢
Get them to me as quick as you can. Thanks.
我的天
Jesus.
他们让那些士兵自生自灭
They're gonna leave those guys down there.
他搭美国航空915号班机
He's on American 915.
晚上七点五十分抵达波哥大
He'll be in Bogota 7:50 p.m.
- 喂？ - 我是里特
- Yeah? - It's Ritter.
你到底跑哪去了？我一直打电话
Where the fuck have you been? I've been calling.
我们有麻烦了
You noticed we have a problem.
麻烦？我们遇到大灾难 我没办法联络我的人！
A problem? We got a disaster. I can't get through to my men!
对，我们必须切断卫星通讯
Yeah, we had to shut down the satellite link.
- 克拉克？  - 必须什么？
- Clark? - Had to what?
是莱恩
It's Ryan.
他发现一切
He found out everything.
扬言要告到国会去
He threatened to walk up the Hill
如果我们不终止行动的话
if we didn't shut down the operation.
好、好
Okay, okay.
那就终止
It's shut down.
只要给我空中支援让我救出我的人
Just give me some air and my men are out of there.
克拉克
Clark,
也许你没听清楚，没有空中支援
maybe you're not hearing me. There is no air.
什么都没有，行动已终止
There is nothing. We are shut down.
我马上搭机
I'm on a plane.
我要宰了他
I'm gonna kill him.
里特？
Ritter?
你不必搭机，他去找你了
You don't have to get on a plane. He's coming to you.
美国航空，七点五十分抵达,没有安全人员
Arriving on American Airlines at 19:50 hours with no security.
你是谁？
Who is this?
国家安全顾问詹姆斯·卡特，克拉克先生
National Security Advisor James Cutter, Mr. Clark,
我保证一旦铲除莱恩，就恢复合作
assuring you that once Ryan's gone, we're back on-line.
明白吗？
You understand?
明白，长官
Yes, sir.
克拉克，嘿，老天
Clark. Hey. Jesus.
进车里去
Get in the van.
别乱来 我是来找你的
Don't be an asshole. I came here to find you.
你找到了，快上车
You found me. Get in.
好吧
All right.
好的
到驾驶座去！
Behind the wheel!
克拉克…
Clark...
开车！
Drive!
- 里特  - 莱恩死了
- Ritter. - Ryan's dead.
怎么死的？
How?
被我杀死的
I killed him.
快恢复通讯吧
Turn the op back on.
- 克拉克… - 你说过
- Clark... - You said,
“铲除莱恩就恢复合作”，对吧？
"Get rid of Ryan and we're back in business," right?
你到底来这里干嘛？
What the hell are you doing here?
我来帮你救出那些士兵
I came to help you get those guys out.
你要怎么帮我？
What can you do to help me?
你需要什么？
What do you need?
一架直升机
A helicopter.
不，谢了
No, thank you.
现在怎样，快乐时光吗？
What is this, happy hour?
天天都是快乐时光
It's always happy hour.
这家店是你的机师的？
Your pilot owns this joint?
他住这里
He lives here.
就是他
Here he is.
- 早安  - 早安
- Good morning. - Good morning.
早安，我想租直升机
Good morning, I'm here to rent the Huey.
抱歉，直升机不出租
Sorry. We don't rent it anymore,
但有出售
but it is for sale.
多少钱？
How much is it?
两百万元
$2 million.
机师和我想试飞看看
My pilot and I would have to take it for a test flight.
当然好，付订金就行了
Yes, of course. You just have to leave a deposit.
要付多少？
How much is that?
两百万元
$2 million.
你收不收公司支票？
Would you take a company check?
（杰克·莱恩 情报局副局长）
收
Yes.
给你吧
Here we go.
真是他妈的大啊，不是吗？
She's a big son of a bitch, ain't she?
你何时飞过这型直升机？
You have any time in this type?
九点的时候
9:00.
离开我的直升机
Get out of my chopper.
不、不，这是我的直升机
No, no, no. My chopper.
起飞吧
Let's go.
最后一次通讯在这里
Their last communication put them here.
最近的撤退点在这里
The closest extraction point is here,
在这峡谷里
in this gorge.
知道了
I got it.
那是尸体吗？
Is that a body down there?
是的
Yeah.
我们的人吗？
One of ours?
我的人
One of mine.
找个地方降落
Find a place to set her down.
我们去找其他人
We'll look for the others.
无处可逃
Nowhere to run to.
无处可藏
No place to hide.
到处都是血渍
Blood trails everywhere.
全都引往河边
They all lead to the river.
这是我们从空中看到的瀑布
These are the falls we saw from the air.
尸体应该在下游50公尺
They should be about 50 meters down.
你抛下了我们！
You left us!
你抛下了我们，完全没支援！
You left us with no support at all!
你抛下我们自生自灭，混蛋…
Clark, you left us out to dry! You son of a...
冷静！冷静！冷静，小子！
Easy, easy, son! Easy, ease up, son!
放开！
Get off!
这不是他的错！
It's not his fault!
那是谁的错？！
Whose fault is it?
是我的错
It's my fault.
我离最后一次攻击地点
I was on point when the last attack came,
一哩多远
over a mile away.
等我赶回去时，一切都结束了
By the time I got back, it was over.
他们带走了队长欧索
They were taking the captain and Oso.
其他人呢？
The others?
被我埋了
I buried them.
那条路通往城里
Road to the town.
他们在这里载走俘虏
They loaded the prisoners here.
血渍斑斑
Blood everywhere.
天知道他们此刻在哪
God knows where they are now.
埃斯科贝多知道
Escobedo knows.
你打算怎么做
What are you going to do,
敲他家门吗？
knock on his door?
早安
Good morning.
我想见埃内斯托·埃斯科贝多
I'd like to see Ernesto Escobedo.
没有事先预约
I don't have an appointment.
好吧
Okay.
双手举起来
Arms up.
双手举起来！
Arms up!
是录音机
It's a tape recorder.
他进去了
He's in.
小鸟，这是变数，请回答
Bird, this is Variable. Over.
莱恩博士
Dr. Ryan.
请进
Come in.
请坐
Sit down.
有什么我能效劳的？
What can I do for you?
我不知道还能找谁
Well, I didn't know who else to turn to.
我有个困难
I have a problem.
我的伙伴，咖啡买家和他的助手
An associate of mine, a coffee buyer and his assistant,
到这区来出差
were on a business trip in this area.
他们昨天无故失踪
They unexpectedly disappeared yesterday.
我很担心
I'm very concerned.
咖啡买家
"Coffee buyer"?
我务必要找到他们
It's very important to me to find them.
咖啡买卖渐渐成为一门危险的生意
Coffee buying is becoming a very dangerous business.
是啊
Yes.
是啊，彼得·哈丁就是如此
Yes. Well, it was for Peter Hardin.
谁？
Who?
他是林度咖啡的客户
He was a client of Lindo Coffee.
林度咖啡有很多客户
Lindo Coffee has many clients.
你一定听说过他
Well, you must have heard of this one.
他欠你们公司一大笔钱
He owed your company a great deal of money.
我得问问会计部
Well, I'll have to talk to accounting about that.
六亿五千万…
$650 million.
还有零钱
And change.
你是来帮我…
Are you offering to help me with the...
收这笔帐吗？
collection of an unpaid debt?
不是
No.
那你想干嘛？
What are you offering?
做个交易
A trade.
费里斯·柯特斯出卖了你
Felix Cortez has sold you out.
他的下一步就是杀光你们全家
His next move is to murder you, your family,
然后接管整个集团
and to take over the cartel.
我的录音带呢？
Where is my tape recorder?
播来听听
Play the tape.
我们走吧
Let's move.
我给你介绍一位新朋友
I'd like you to meet my new friend.
莱恩博士
Dr. Ryan.
医生吗？
Doctor?
有人生病吗？
Why? Is somebody sick?
他要什么？
What does he want?
救回他的伙伴
The safe return of his associates.
他要用什么来换？
And what does he offer us in return?
你
You.
这家伙说的全是谎话
Whatever this man has told you is a lie.
他靠说谎过活
He lies for a living.
- 他是情报员  - 没错
- He's in the intelligence business. - Exactly.
你也是情报员！
You're in the intelligence business!
你解决了那几条小鱼
You've taken care of the little fish.
我来解决漏网那条大鱼
I will take care of the one that got away.
一旦铲除了埃斯科贝多
Once Escobedo is gone,
我就可以顺理成章地帮你
I will be in a position to help you.
所以…问题是…
So, the question is
我该拿你怎么办？
what am I supposed to do with you?
该用这根球棒把你活活打死！
Well, I guess I'm supposed to kill you with this bat!
你对自己的产品说太多了
I'd say you've been taking too much of your own product.
我也可以跟你保证…
I can also promise you...
站起来！
Get up!
破获大宗案件，你的警方可以立功…
regular quotas on major arrests that your police can take credit for.
破案率大增，毒品锐减
Dramatic seizures, drastic reductions,
再也没有无谓的暴力事件
no more violence to speak of.
你会取得胜利
You'll have your victory.
代价是什么？
In return for what?
切断他们的通信
Cut off their communications.
- 他们在哪里？  - 就在这里
- Where are they? - They're here.
封锁工厂！
Seal the plant!
美国人杀了埃内斯托！
The American killed Ernesto!
快点！快走！快走！
Come on! Move! Let's go!
小鸟呼叫变数，请回答
Bird to Variable. Over.
小鸟，这是变数
Bird, this is Variable.
你到底在哪里？
Where the hell are you?
我大约在村庄往南五公里处盘旋，结束
Well, I'm cruising about five clicks south of the village. Over.
留在那里
Stay there.
再连络
I'll get back to you.
知道了
Roger that.
没人
No one.
战俘！
The prisoners.
快点，各位，我们走了
Come on, guys. Let's go, son.
我们要回家了，兄弟
We're going home, boys.
到林度咖啡工厂接我们
Pick us up at the Lindo coffee factory.
从你的立场来看
From your point of view,
可以排除潜在的安全问题，不是吗？
it eliminates a potential security problem, does it not?
不只我可以向媒体揭发你
Not only can I expose you to the press,
那些士兵也可以
so can the soldiers.
你想冒险吗？
You want to risk it?
你想赌赌看吗？
You want to take your chances
面对法庭、国会议员
with the courts and congressional committees
新闻记者和全世界？
and television reporters and the world?
你想结束当最高统帅的政治生涯吗？
You want to end the political career of your commander-in-chief?
我们走吧！
Let's go!
快点进来！快！我们要走了！
Get your asses in here! Come on! We gotta go!
快点！快跑！快进来！
Come on! Run! Get your butts in here!
慢点！我们要等莱恩！
Hold it! We wait for Ryan!
什么？我们得走了！
Yeah! We're out of here!
快下去！
Set it down!
他在下面！
He's down there!
快点！
Come on!
我抓住你了！
I got you!
崔维斯，掩护我！
Chavez, cover me!
你的手！把你的手给我！
Your hand! Give me your hand!
总统现在要见你了
The President will see you now, sir.
杰克，很高兴见到你
Jack. I'm glad you're here.
请坐
Sit down.
要喝什么吗？
Can I get you anything?
不用了
No.
来吧，坐下来
Come on. Sit down.
我想站着，总统
I would prefer to stand, sir.
有一些事…
Some things have gone on here
…我刚刚才获悉
that I'm just becoming aware of.
我跟你一样，被蒙在鼓里好一阵子
I was kept in the dark, as you were, for a very long time.
棘手的事
Troubling things.
是啊
Yeah.
现在我们必须彻底了解
And now we have to sort them out.
厘清谁该负什么责任
We have to figure out who is responsible for what,
以及该如何解决
and what to do about it.
我们必须很小心地处理
And we have to do this very delicately
否则人们会误解
otherwise people might get the wrong idea.
我们必须说谎
We have to lie.
我有说吗？
Did I say that?
不，你没说
No, you didn't.
你很失望
You're upset.
我很失望
I'm upset.
情有可缘
Well, it's understandable.
介意我给你一点忠告吗？
You mind if I give you a bit of advice?
当然，你知道的因为你是个聪明人
Of course, you know this because you're a smart guy.
绝不要做重大决定
You should never make important decisions
在你失望的时候
while you're upset.
你却做了
You did,
美国士兵和无辜平民还因此送命
and American soldiers and innocent civilians are dead because of it.
我从没下令…
I never ordered any...
不，别跟我来这一套
No, don't even think about playing that game with me.
我不会任由你假装若无其事
I will not let you dishonor their memories
而让他们白白牺牲
by pretending you had nothing to do with it.
你怎么敢进来这里跟我说教？
How dare you come in here and lecture me?
那你怎么敢，总统？
How dare you, sir?
你怎么敢进到这办公室
How dare you come into this office
像只疯狗对我乱叫！
and bark at me like some little junkyard dog?
我可是美国总统！
I am the President of the United States!
我也很不愿意，总统
It gives me no pleasure to do it, sir.
身为情报局代理副局长
As Acting Deputy Director of Intelligence,
我有责任对监督委员会报告这件事
it is my duty to report this matter to the Senate Oversight Committee.
你不会那么做的
You're not gonna do that.
- 我不会吗？ - 不，不
- I'm not? - No, no.
此刻你在这场大赌局里掌握了一个筹码
You've got yourself a chip in the big game now.
你要把它藏好
You're gonna tuck that away.
留在最紧急关头时再拿出来用
You are gonna save that for a time when your own ass is on the line,
等你打算拿出来用时
and then you're gonna pull it out
我会给你兑换的
and I'm gonna cash it in for you.
对吧？
Right?
我想跟你没什么好谈的，总统
I don't think I have anything more to say to you, sir.
这个国家承受不起另一个丑闻，杰克
The country can't afford another scandal, Jack.
为了保护国家
To protect itself,
国家不会让诡计
it won't allow the possibility of another deception
影响到最高层的长官
that goes all the way to the top.
你会成为代罪羔羊
You'll take the blame.
卡特和里特也会负点责任
Cutter and Ritter will take some, too,
不过不会太严重
but it won't amount to much.
只会受到小小处罚
They'll get a slap on the wrist
并且在审查期间，每小时补偿两万元
and then $20,000 an hour on the lecture circuit.
其他的责任会推给格里尔
The rest of the blame will fall on Greer.
哦，对，你会拖他下水
Oh, yeah, you'll take him down with you.
你会毁了他的名誉
You'll destroy his reputation,
不过事情将会到此为止
but that's as far as it will go.
古老的波托马克二步舞曲，杰克
The old Potomac two-step, Jack.
抱歉，总统先生
I'm sorry, Mr. President.
我不跳舞
I don't dance.
莱恩，你有空吗？
Ryan, have you got a minute?
没有
No.
我们必须谈谈
We need to talk.
莱恩！
Ryan!
委员会会议正式开始
The committee will please come to order.
主席现在传唤约翰·莱恩博士
The chair will now call Dr. John Ryan.
莱恩博士，谢谢你出席
Dr. Ryan, thank you very much
今天的委员会会议
for appearing before the committee today.
谢谢你，主席
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
请起立，举起你的右手
Please stand and raise your right hand.
你愿意郑重发誓
Do you solemnly swear
你在这委员会面前所说的一切
that the testimony you're about to give before this committee
全部都是事实，没有别的，只有事实
is the truth, the whole truth and nothing but the truth,
愿主保佑你吗？
so help you God?
我愿意
I do.
莱恩博士，你做了宣誓了
Dr. Ryan, you may consider yourself under oath.
请坐下
Please be seated.